Amer Lotfi Orimi

amerllica@gmail.com +989202016078 Madani Tehran, Tehran

Summary

I'm a passionate front-end engineer. I'm experienced in JavaScript, Web/App UI Development, HTML/CSS, ReactJS and React Native. My fields of interest include front-end development, building projects from scratch, maintaining legacy projects, migrating the architecture from legacy to new ones, and UI/UX design. I'm so eager about new technologies and readily accept new challenges. I'd love to write blog posts and articles and answer Stack Overflow questions in my spare time—also a big fan of using TypeScript in front-end projects.

Employment History

Freelance Frontend Engineer (remote)

TRIBES · London, UK 06/2022 - Present

Tribes is a company, it is like an umbrella, it has its own projects but it is working alongside many companies. Other companies request help from Tribes and Tribes send the developers like agents there to work with them and build the products.

React Native Developer at Dubit (contract base) (remote)

TRIBES · Leeds, UK 06/2022 - 03/2023

I have designed an architecture for their application. The application was about playing podcasts for kids. The application has several actions and also a specific module for painting. I used RNTP for playing songs and React Native Skia for implementing the painting module. The painting module was one of the tough parts that I awesomely I have done it. I wrote an article on Medium about my experiences with the painting module.

App links:

- iOS
- Android

Frontend and Business Consultant (remote)

IT&T · San Francisco, CA 06/2022 - Present

After working two years on the Lobox social network, I'm still waiting for its success, so I can't spend time anymore on it but still, for consulting, I'm open to IT&T to help them.

Frontend Engineer (remote)

IT&T · San Francisco, CA 07/2021 - 06/2022

After 8 months of leading the Frontend team, I decided to transfer the leadership to a better teammate who was better and fitter in this situation.

Frontend Team Lead (remote)

IT&T · San Francisco, California

12/2020 - 07/2021

We are reinventing Social Networks, it is our motto, actually, we are creating a competitor of LinkedIn. At the first of my entrance, I made up the team, brought the good Frontend and Backend developers and then create a

very robust structure for the project.

I brought ReactJs with SSR, still, we are developing the features and the team is up now. features and the team is up now.

Links:

- production
- development

Frontend Engineer

Sibche · Tehran, Tehran 05/2020 - 12/2020

Actually, Sibche is an iOS store market, and I was responsible for the main app of this store, the main technology was React Native. I was developing the main app and other companies' apps based on React Native. For the whole of the project, I used TypeScript, Test, and the latest technologies.

Frontend Engineer

Sheypoor • Tehran, Tehran Province

05/2018 - 05/2020

Sheypoor is one of the classified websites in Iran. Its work area is very professional and I practiced a lot of things like pair programming and planning methods for large-scale projects there. Also, I worked deeply on React-Native. I had previous knowledge of React-Native from before and have built a small application. However, at Sheypoor I experienced it from scratch and worked it very deeply. My work experiences also include:

- Design ReactJS/RN UI Elements, Navigation, Composite Components, etc.
- Pair Programming and Pair Reviewing Front-end Codes (Web/App)
- Prepare Android/iOS Build Scripts for React Native
- · Configure Webpack, ESLint, etc.

Frontend Developer

Scann · Tehran, Tehran Province

12/2017 - 05/2018

Scann was a Fintech startup, I was encouraged to work there because their stack had to be written from scratch. So I decided to work with them to create a big challenge for myself.

- Design and Develop 3 Large-scale Apps
- Implement Redux and Redux Thunk
- Implement a Boilerplate for React Apps
- Node.js and ReactJS

Frontend Web Developer

Digikala.com · Tehran, Tehran Province

11/2016 - 12/2017

My primary duty in Digikala was to develop Web UI. I had to make Digikala better in UX and improve its conversion rate, including:

- Improved the UX of the mobile app and fix the serious bug that nobody was able to track since. The conversion rate of the Firefox mobile app was zero because of the poor JavaScript codebase. I fixed it and it also solved its other issues
- We refactored the search page. We implemented it as a single-page React application. However, it vanished after Digikala's big-bang update.
- I was involved in the Partial Shipment project which was so valuable for the managers.
- I got moved to Digikala Mag and comprehensively refactored it. We separated the Desktop and mobile apps.

I practiced a lot of technologies and patterns, such as HTML5, Razor, CSS3, adaptive design, responsive design, flexbox, SVG animations SMIL, Neat, Bourbon, BEM, Less, SCSS, PostCSS, JavaScript(ES6), React, Redux, Babel, Gulp, Webpack, and etc.

Links:

- Digikala
- Digikala Mag

Technical Support Specialist and UI Developer

Douran.com · Tehran, Tehran Province

10/2010 - 11/2016

Douran had a CMS that sold to many companies and government offices, every customer was a separate task, the most important job was designing a wireframe, and the customer wanted the website looks like it. Then fix it to have a better UX and then assign it to a UI designer, after the design I present it to the customer and got the authorization and start to develop it into an HTML/CSS/JS package. for Responsively I was using Bootstrap and UI Kit, absolutely I read about Less and SCSS and developed my tasks with CSS preprocessors and JavaScript Library like jQuery. after 6 years I saw there weren't any new challenges for me and I wanted to grow up my knowledge and salary. so I decide to leave Douran and join to Digikala.

Professional Skills

Web Development, Front-end Development, JavaScript, ReactJS, HTML, CSS, React Native, SCSS/Sass, Webpack, Ecmascript6+, TypeScript, Docker, Application Development, Git, Team Management

Education

Master Degree

Kharazmi University · Tehran, Tehran Province

Graduated 02/2013

I have studied **Knowledge Engineering and Decision Science**, Most of the topics were about artificial intelligence and analyzing massive data for making better decisions.

Bachelor Degree

Damghan University · Damghan, Semnan Province

Graduated 07/2009

Applied Mathematics, I love it and I miss it. Applied Mathematics makes me strong in analyzing and meticulous in problem-solving.

Languages

Persian, German, Turkish, English